we're gonna start with the alarm Rim
because we need to read something so we
can meditate on it okay and it's a nice
meditation for your retreat which starts
today at two o'clock
and you have a choice to do it or not to
do it
and if you do it your life will change
drastically if you don't do it it'll
just keep going the same old way
so I really encourage you it's just two
days okay we did a thousand days
[Music]
days it's a good start
a good days of Silence
and it's really really good for you
I think
putting away your phone is almost as
important as to this
I found out I have to lock my phone up
and they're oh a new product Rosa for
our
gmr luxury brand
is a satchel with a time lock on it
seriously
and you lock your phone up for like 48
hours
seriously seriously
that remind me to remind Rose okay all
right
[Music]
so we'll start at two o'clock we'll
close the boundaries
and when we close the boundaries here
we we are also closing them on our
remote retreats
which includes the greatest country in
the world Vietnam
and also Ukraine and Russia we have
Retreats good okay so uh you guys will
be closing your boundaries also
also please uh
keep a good two days here okay
that's why you came here that's why you
spent all the money to come
here it's
it's a really really expensive to have
this place and it's 20
23 years of hard work really hard work
Blood Sweat and Tears we say
so use the goddamn place okay and do a
retreat okay don't come here and just do
your cell phone thing
all right if one person
keeps silence for two days I'll be happy
two people do I will dance
all right okay please
and your life will change
your life
and then I I would like to do some
longer Retreats here
silence
start with two days
[Music]
okay
innovation
uh we're gonna start at
baloney did you find it it's again
all right let's read
[Music]
this is where he says when you take uh
with the razor blade right Mr
what's his name
Robbie
and you cut the razor you cut the
Blackness okay then he says here don't
just put the Blackness you know
on your kitchen table
and I could say
yeah
that
that's misspelled in the
in the carving but we we'll let it go
for now uh it's jig Young
d-n-g-a-g-d-n-g-a-n-g-s
[Music]
but don't worry about it okay now if you
get scared that's a good thing okay okay
I feel nervous
uh bringing that Blackness into your
heart
that's a good thing that means your your
visualization's doing well by the way
we're gonna go much deeper in that
visualization today
and so this is just the most basic one
it's much deeper one
I guess
means that's good for a hundred dollars
who can tell me a famous example of that
one
not you
who said
yeah hundred dollars
extra dollar if you tell me the sense
where does it come from
you gotta do the work if you want the
money
where does it come from
yeah
which one
okay
yeah it means great right so Buddha
tells oh
great great
what's the irony of that
what's the irony of Buddha telling
telling in the Heart Center great great
yeah he forced him to say what he said
then he said oh you spoke so well
okay all right anyway
if you think like that we also learn my
new count look you cannot really take
the other person's pain away
okay there it is in black and white
Musso means directly then take it Manu
you don't have the power young but
you will collect massive amounts of good
and that will give you the karma
okay
and if you get used to that kind of
collection of massive Karma you can
actually take away other people's pain
and then he says
story
like a colloquial story just between
France you know
and then Champion means
a yogim
a person who's practicing yoga
and then sometimes it refers to a
tantric practitioner
when you see the name of a daddy just in
front of
that usually means like a vajugini
specialist or some
so here is a jumper specialist
he's a maitrea specialist he's he's
doing his Diamond week practice focused
on my trip
and then this is one of those
frustrating places
in this massive long Rim which is going
to take us 15 years to finish right
where he says uh you guys know this
story I don't have to tell you
and we're like yeah right
and uh so
um art Engel who translated this book in
three
with my teacher
he found all the stories
back in the days before the database
he he flipped two books for for 15 years
and uh so anyway the story is this
uh
somebody with there's a teacher named
kusali
and there's two kusalis there's an older
one and a younger one they are famous
for being in the emptiness lineage
[Music]
story is found in a famous book called
which means
the life stories of all the London
teachers
and that's about a 2000 page classic
it's in the database
and it's very precious because it has
the biographies of every major and
London teacher
It's a Wonderful book in fact DCI just
gave a grant
to a website called the treasury of
lives which is translating those stories
for about the last 10 years
and they have about 1500 stories online
and they need some mixed nuts training
but it's not bad so we gained over ten
thousand dollar Grant
uh I hope you paid it yeah okay uh I
gotta check
so the following incident is described
there
this kusali was teaching the Dharma and
somebody nearby hit a dog with a stick
and then the teacher said
and fell down
and then I'm already looked at the dog
and there's nothing wrong with the dog
the dog's like wagging his tail
and everybody's like oh this is a big
fake this guy's a big fake you know
and and he said if you think I'm a fake
look check this out and he took his
shirt off
and he showed his back and there's this
big well where the stick
hit the dog
was on the teachers that
you could see the wound on the teacher's
bed
and he took them he took it from the dog
in a moment
so that's proof
that if we get really good at it we
maybe we could take some in special
cases
other people's people
honey
when we do the giving
which of the two attitudes or which of
the two
emotions are we are we specializing in
yeah okay yeah so when you do the giving
he says
then he's going to go off on a major
topic
and we're going to spend some time on it
okay
okay and I'd like you to focus on that
during your two-day retreat
it's a beautiful practice
[Music]
and this comes from Shanti Deva from
Master shelter
a guide to the body's office where
you should try to achieve the goals of
of beings
turn your body into a wishing Jewel
turn your body into a wishing Joy into
money you should okay
and uh
the whole uh
I like the whole He quotes two lines
right a verse is four lines
and
if you have John Brady's database
and by the way uh
we it's 35 years that we've been
inputting books
and uh
we've had fat years and lean years
so we've had very years when we got into
a huge debt I was once indent almost a
hundred thousand dollars
and then we've had years that were going
very well
I have to say uh these last few years
were going very well
and that's because of you guys that's
because of all universities so I'm
really grateful for that it takes a lot
of pressure off of me
I'm always in the background on that
project
I'm the person they go to when they run
out of money
and uh
they haven't come to me for three four
five years and I really appreciate it
and you guys are doing the gold clubs
especially all right so let's look you
guys are doing great jobs
I'm really grateful they the gold clubs
in the Russian language sphere and
ukrainians speaking here
have raised over a million
in five dollar donations
so that's
I'm really grateful for
anyway because we have database I can
teach
and here we go uh
here's from the database
[Music]
below you guys
skip down two paragraphs dark the bull
the bull
s
here's the rest of the verse okay which
is only possible because of the Gold
Club and similar people
day
Dr December
uh
if you get good at this practice
Shin here doesn't mean similar
here it means faith
likeness your likeness okay
and ghee is the imperative here it's not
the instrumental
do it
and
Zoom me
like a zoom call
a zoom call
Zoom means uh smiling
okay Zoom
okay I guess zoomco is good okay do
means smiling he says if you get good at
this practice you're gonna walk around
with a dumb grin on your face all day
long
you know and it's who said that
Shanti demon he says I'll teach you a
practice
and if you get good at it you're gonna
walk around all the time with a big
smile on your face
all right
and this goes to a very deep topic and
I'm gonna frustrate Tim further
by going off on a tangent
because I like to
so here we go
[Music]
you guys got Ben's
book cover
there's a new book that we finished uh I
don't know a month ago it took six or
seven years
uh the mixed nuts finished it it's uh
this is the book it's called great ideas
of the East
it's a survey of 101 enlightening
beliefs
it's a huge book it's like this
this we just finished it
it's got a hundred and one
different belief systems
the 101st
guess which school
yeah higher Midway higher okay
and that one in the book is about a
hundred pages
okay so and there's a hundred other
belief systems
and they are fascinating they're
and we've been teaching them in around
we've been test driving this book this
book will be the basis of DCI advanced
level 3. which is being written this
month
and uh
and it'll be uh it'll come out in
November but it's based on Ben Cramer's
and I need to
it's an awesome book and it's it's it
should be available shortly they are
doing the final blah blah
and and uh who helped Anatole helped
uh uh in this book
he mentions 110 colonies
of enlightenment
different mental States
and uh
he and so we he mentions it and we went
and found them
and we added it to the book from John
gritty's Gold Club database
so uh it's never been translated before
there's a 110
beautiful extraordinary mental States
described that's in the 101st World War
okay so the 101st worldview has a 110
mental qualities that you can develop
one of them
is called safer contingency
and it has a brother called Silk silky
number gay and I'd like to talk about
those
so when you do your gushier degree
normally the class starts out with about
60 people
and uh
people die people quit
and it gets down to about
I don't know 10 people
and about four or five years before the
gesture Zoo
and then they do a cut they do a
pre-gussion cut
s and they cut
and uh so you get a
you get a debate topic the debate master
hands you a little tiny piece of paper
and that's your debate talking
and mine was
uh
which is a super weird
topic stinging Zen you know means
concentrate Focus you know single
pointed concentration
deep meditation
separ means finished
separ means completed
and it's a special kind of meditation
and you're gonna have to do it to do the
dungland today and tomorrow in your
retreat
you're gonna have to learn some separate
things in to uh to do the
to do the donland property
and it's it's very deep
and it's and it
it's something we should study and
something we should
write a book about
indeed beautiful practice okay
uh basically
and by the way I
I did really bad in that debate
I got murdered in that debate
I still passed
but uh I'll never forget it because I
was embarrassed in front of a few
thousand people
so this is a dear topic to me uh so
because then I went and became an expert
at okay so uh
uh and We're translating a second book
nowadays We're translating 12 books
[Music]
the second one that we're just finishing
up this week is Sudan's book it took
about six years five six years
and uh
it's about the Wheel of Life
and so the Wheel of Life was
was designed by Lord Buddha
uh on three different occasions there
are three different stories
how he designed the Wheel of Life
and we chose a beautiful story
to put in sugan's book which is a Sutra
and it's about a lady named muktika
story of how Lord Buddha painted The
Wheel of Life
for a woman follower
who lived in Sri Lanka 2 000 miles away
and she was too far away to come to
Central India to shravasti for class
so he sent her the painting
with the instructions and then she
she studied the instructions she studied
the painting and she saw emptiness in
within a week
okay and uh it's a beautiful story of a
woman Arya so aryas are extremely rare
and I think it's the only woman are you
that I that I remember the whole story
woman are you okay okay so that's in
we put the whole Sutra into gang's text
and John Brady's team found the
sunscreen so we have the Sanskrit to
Tibetan and
then we uh
000 years later
well Buddha told people I want this real
because it's so powerful I want a copy
in every Monastery Temple
and I want it at the doorway
and because I want people to be forced
to look at it every time they come into
Temple so since those days it became a
tradition to to put the Wheel of Life
painting
the door
when you first come in into a temple
and five a thousand years later they
were still doing it
and
by a thousand years later
they had started to make other drawings
and there's a list in the vinaya Sutra
of drawings for specific spots like in
the debate ground there should be this
drawing
on the on the West Wall of your retreat
cabin there should be this joint
and there's about 20 different
prescribed
drawings why am I going off in this huge
tangent
one of those drawings is supposed to be
a five color wheel
just a wheel with five colors
okay five root four or five root colors
in primary colors
in in Buddhism in the Abu Dharma okay
you're just supposed to paint swatches
of colors on the wall
and in general in Buddhism
in real Buddhism
we never ever my teacher
so he used to say never ever right Rob
North no Emma you never meditate
staring at something
we don't use outer objects as a
meditation you don't you can look at the
Wheel of Life
for a while and then go close your eyes
and meditate
but we don't in this tradition we think
uh to stare at a painting or to stare at
a statue
is to run it's not subtle enough you
can't develop focus on that
you can stare at a statue it's a nice
thing it's a good thing to do
especially if you're sitting in a temple
or something
but it's not meditation
it's not developing
okay some money
but
there is there is a case
where you can stare at colors and you
are required to paint them on the wall
of your drink up
and you do stare at them
and then you you learn to use them in
your deep meditation okay and and that's
a weird practice called silky number gay
which means the eight uh
repressions
repression means to push down on
something right like you repress these
feelings you know you want to yell in
the class and you
you control yourself you press yourself
okay so there's a practice called the
aid repressions
and it's a very high practice
and
maybe I'll give it maybe I'll I'll read
it to you okay from Ben's book uh it's
tough
give me one second to go find it
uh Ben's book is one of the few places
where you can
yeah cool uh
section 694.
h
a ton of pages long
thick it's deep every page is deep
so here's our practice it's called the
eight repressions
it's related to staring at colors
painted on the side of your retreat
okay
which is related to The Wheel of Life
so Ben's book and sugan's book are
connected
and all the 12 books connect somehow
[Music]
um
you you gain an ability I'll just read
from Ben's book okay to manipulate or
emanate various shapes and colors allows
you to overwhelm other people so they're
called the eight overwhelmings
okay especially unruly people
so like uh
if a student is really being naughty you
can emanate ourselves
what do we have yesterday brown bear
Snow bear
tiger
poisonous snakes Okay like you can this
is the practice
in Buddhism
where you learn to emanate as other
things
this is the foundation
of the practice
where later you can
you can be any person you want
and
you can emanate as a tree
and you can emanate as a bridge
beautiful
things like that so so this is the
practice
it's called
I like to think of it as messing with
colors and shapes
okay it's the ability
to manipulate
colors and shapes because of your
meditation if you start now
in this two-day retreat later it will
ripen and you'll be able to emanate in
different ways to help different people
you can emanate as a highway you can
emanate as a skyscraper you can emanate
as a mountain
you can emanate as an insect okay it's
really fun and really cool so we're
gonna plant the seeds for it during
these two days okay
and I've never taught you that
and it's from these two books okay and
that's why we're trying to get these
books out desperately trying to get the
time
to get the books out and it's really
hard
okay
so why are there eight are you ready
first of all uh these are called silky
Numa
which means overwhelm somebody for two
reasons
number one
if you learn to emanate us if you have a
student who's being not
who refuses to shut up during the 48
Hours of retreat
uh you could like emanate as a bear
and and uh
say ah get back in your cabin okay
I mean there's a lot of use to be able
to show any form you want right and
that's a classic Buddha ability and
these two days we're gonna plant the
seeds okay
and I'm not
guaranteeing that in 48 hours you're
going to be able to be a bear
uh unless yours again or something but
uh
but you're planting the seeds planting
this is and obviously by the way he says
these four are also called overwhelming
for another reason
is that you can
you can help people you can amaze people
you can guide people and then secondly
overwhelming silky number means
you gain control of colors and shapes
okay so the reason you might paint
these four or five colors on this why
Buddha said two and a half thousand
years ago I want The Wheel of Life at
the doorway
and I want some colors painted on the
wall
where you meditate are you supposed to
stare at the colors
no that's not meditation but they will
remind you to do these other meditations
with your eyes closed
that will allow you to manipulate
colors and shapes and then there's eight
variations you ready
okay number one
[Music]
um
so you
first of all you would focus
in a meditation you would close your
eyes
and you would imagine that
for example
practice you're gonna do in the next two
days okay
and this is in the Lum realm this is
induction this is another form of
exchanging self
now this is another form of dongland
you should come
to the hell realms
as a as a rain cloud
as a nice diamond mountain rain cloud
so
you have to uh
you have to
imagine with your eyes closed
yourself
as a rain cloud in the hot house
and you have to rain on everybody
okay so I want you to do practice
during the two days
this is stungland right you are giving
to people
you're going through the realms
that are in the real of life it's called
the five Realms in that in that ancient
world
and you go to the hell rounds and you go
to the hot house
and you're gonna emanate as a ring club
that rain cloud is uh
tiny in your mind
and that's called overwhelming why you
reduce the ring Club okay you you take a
big rain cloud that would cover the
whole Retreat value
and you close your eyes and you shrink
and that's called silky number that's
called overwhelming
shrink the rain cloud
in your mind so that you can get into it
and become it
and then you then you send yourself back
out as a huge rain cloud okay got it so
you're gonna
imagine you're gonna think about a huge
rain cloud that would cover all of them
then you're gonna overwhelm it which
means you're going to shrink it to it
a chance that would fit
in your mind then you're gonna get into
the rain cloud and then you're gonna
send it out again got it okay
and you are manipulating
the outside world
and that's that's a high Buddhist
practice that you haven't heard much
about
you you've heard that
Buddhists can emanate as a tree as a
bridge but these are the meditations
that plant the seed that allow you to do
it later
and it's very beautiful it's a very
beautiful practice obviously
there has to be which of the two
emotions
love there has to be oh my God these
people are burning these people are
these people are running naked
cross a frying pan
the Hothouse floor
is is a metal frying
like 100 miles long and they are running
across a
a red hot frying pan all day long
so then you're gonna thumb there you're
gonna say God you guys need some relief
I will rain on you
well how are you gonna do that well I
guess I'll have to be a rain cloud today
and then you do this meditation you take
a big rain cloud image that you've seen
shrink it in your meditation get into it
like a Volkswagen bug
and then expand it again and then go to
the hell rounds and rain on everybody
got it
all right
next one
large physical constructs so this is
where you could become a bridge
or a large building for someone like
like you you imagine
and and we'll talk about it
the third one
uh
you you make outside forms disappear you
take the rain cloud and you make it
disappear in your mind
and that allows you to reduce
outer forms Ant-Man
right
okay there is such a thing and then the
opposite for expanding forms
you can make small things big you can
make big things small
uh and then there's four
uh overpowerings of color
which means you meditate on the colors
the rude colors blue yellow white and
red
blue yellow white
and you meditate on those colors
and you gain
power
to create blue and to create red and
white
that that is your palette
that's your uh
what do you call that thing that the
painter holds and they have all the
paints on it
palette yeah so
it's a meditation palette for all
possible colors and shapes
from that you can make clouds
for the hell Realms you can become a
clown
before the hell runs so the last four
are the color palette the first four are
the shape and and size palette and then
in your meditation you paint a a rain
cloud and then you get into it and you
emanate it and you become it okay it's
very beautiful a very beautiful title
and we're going to be doing that
what about the cold house
by the way my computer just died so give
me a second ah cold hell
what would be nice to emanate for them
what does he say
yeah like
nice jackets or something
I think that's what the local government
is
so
wait till my computer comes
so for the hot house which is the main
house
you do
a rain cloud
and I want you to practice for the two
days
and then for the
cold health
I guess
uh warmth oh I'm sorry I remember
he says why don't we just use the yellow
color palette
and the and the circle shape color
palette and why not we flip the
overpowering from Tiny to huge we set
the
the meditation to go from Tiny to huge
and become
this time
okay so I will I I will be the son
we have a picture I think Daniel
[Music]
I think it's a son I'm not sure or sunny
forest or something
yeah
so
you are the Sun
[Music]
uh
okay and uh this could be the cold
health
and nobody's cold anymore
because you understand
and uh
the point is in these two days
of retreat we're gonna plant the seeds
to be able
to
emanate as a son
as a planet
and don't think small in this business
we are shrinking and we are expanding
right we already said that so don't
think small you know don't think oh I'll
do a firefly
in the cold Health okay
that's an old Tibetan joke
don't don't think small
be a son
and I want you to
use your imagination that's the practice
and it has been recommended for two and
a half thousand years
think big
and emanate as a son
okay for the cold health
um
come on back
it's coming it's just print sometimes my
computer
in Kyoto it did not like
I don't know why but during the street
saying that he
did it like
come on
it's not really
okay well let's just wing it uh after
you finish the heart health and the cold
health I got it too it just came back
thank you though thank you uh let me see
the emanate as a computer
uh
okay
uh the text says Dunbar I'm on Dunbar
okay d-a-n-g space p o r
it's like the next paragraph
y number two thing he says not just a
normal rain
I want nectar ring
I want a cloud that can make nectar
what kind of nectar that's listening
neck diamonds what in Greek
neck means necrophilia
go beyond
nectar means America it's a beautiful
it's the same word
I don't want water falling in the hot
house I want nectar
which means deathless nectar
number two thing emanate that Daniel
John clean away all their
suffering
of the hell days okay
then are we doing Leonard thong
we're kind of doing things so he says by
the way since we're on thong since we're
on giving
I want you to give them a townjor
which is into gang's text also we added
a huge appendix 18 niches and torches I
want them to have a teacher I want them
to have John British database
I want them to have a good income
you know I want them to have a nice
house where
in the house
okay all right okay like thank God
Indian restaurant opens up there
stuff like that weird beautiful stuff
somebody opened an Indian restaurant
it's then I know I'm I'm close to
Nirvana okay
uh downtown again I never thought it
would happen in my life
okay
[Music]
by the way why don't we give them Luxury
Apartments
okay how
it's you
okay
all right so expand your stomach make it
square
put nice carpet sofa
okay got it you become a luxury
apartment
and they can they can
I mean you can see all these hot held
guys just walking out to the apartment
wow
I wonder if the you know I wonder if the
they got a 100 inch TV or something
my family our family email it's always
like
one of my brothers is like now I got a
200 inch TV the other one's like no I
got a 360
okay so you can be a 300 inch TV in the
luxury apartment that grew out of your
stomach for the hot hell people okay all
right you know I'm a grinning
and then imagine them coming into you
as a luxury apartment and enjoying it
that's a beautiful practice
and that's what you're gonna do for two
days
moving into you
the hell beings are moving into you
jumping on the bed you know uh rating
the refrigerator
like that okay be be think big okay
because when you become a Buddha that's
what you're gonna be doing
okay so plant this is now
just imagine
I just became a luxury apartment like a
Singapore
five room apart there's only two in
one is owned by the Sultan of Brunei I
know
okay and you're like I'm gonna be a six
room luxury apartment in Singapore you
know all right Journey
second Prince of secure
you're here means transform yourself
you're a very beautiful verb okay you're
transform yourself into say and come
which is punto means a disha
excellent perfect
food and drink okay stock up the frizz
with your favorite you know mineral
water 23 dollars a bottle
you know you're you're the bottle you're
the cap you're the water and you open
yourself
okay and the hell the hell beans are
yeah yeah
it's my favorite brand I wish they had
it in sparkling and then boom you're
like oh I can do that and then you're
sparkling okay got it like have fun okay
no
have fun with it okay
because you are literally planning the
seeds to do it really
okay and if you don't plant the seeds
you're delaying your Buddha
if you just talk during the whole
Retreat and and look at the news on your
phone secretly hoping grandpa doesn't
see you
have special powers
okay
maybe uh
then Kissinger your means turn yourself
into
nice clothes
silk pajamas
you know hey you hell around me
you know stop don't you want some soup
pajamas yeah
Don't You Wanna
I don't know
where'd you get those shirts Japanese
nice Japanese shirts
Liam is gone
beautiful clothes for them
think of beautiful ways to do to dress
them up
and you are the class okay you're not
dressing them up you are the clothes
you're like a pair of pants that finally
fits you know Nick told me
there's a demon in
San Diego
that sneaks into your closet
it shrinks your waistband and
so you could be
when is that stretchy stuff
you could be Lycra for the hell round
beads
pants you know
and you know so use your imagination
okay these two days I think it's a fun
assignment for a two-day silent retreat
okay
what else would be nice Gateway
turn into a Geisha that's the long word
for guess
which literally means kalyana Mitra
which means Dharma teacher Dharma
teacher become a spiritual guide for
them you guys happy you got enough to
eat yeah you like the apartment
whoa
anyway don't look uh
turn into and then when you're done with
everything else
turn into a great Dharma teacher and say
if you're going to stay in this luxury
apartment and drink this bottled
sparkling water and wear these silk
pajamas you gotta sit down and have a
class
and then emanate yourself as a teacher
in the luxury apartment where are you
you're still in the hell Road
at that point how can it still be a hell
realm if you've transformed it like that
first you've ever been in a long
teaching in this room make you feel that
way
[Music]
like you have to go to the bathroom it
just like going off on this tangent
all right uh
and then finally
means because you taught them the Dharma
is the verb of Sange
they be they you bruticize them
you buddhicize them
okay wow what happened I got Buddha
sized
where in the hell room in the luxury
apartment who did it cats cat turned
into a Buddha and bruticized me
okay got it
so that that's a happy ending to the
story of the hell River okay that's your
assignment for the two days
that's just the hell realm we got five
other rooms okay
okay red you want to go on let's go on
okay here we go
they named
[Music]
and then he's kind of like gonna go
faster he's gonna say okay when you get
to the cold house do your thing
you know like you can figure it out he
gives a couple of examples
you could be a beam of warm soft
sunlight coming into the window
you know wouldn't that be nice to be the
sunlight
to be the warm sunlight on the skin of a
being that's been freezing for
Ten Thousand Years
be the sunlight on their skin
and then cursor cursive means uh
dress them up in toasty clothing
sweaters and stuff
and stuff and then he says soak soak
means I leave it up to your imagination
so actually he split the helm realm into
two
and when you see The Wheel of Life you
can see it split into
it uh
now next what's he gonna talk about
what's logical next
to bed you're done
there's the spelling
dvags
uh what would you docs like you to turn
in food and drink say means food comment
straight and don't be lazy make it a
nice French dinner or something
I I have my mom had a stroke my stepmom
she's 95.
stuck in this rehab place
and so me and Veronica went there last
week
we busted her out in the wheelchair
and the guard tried to stop us and we're
like mine we got out
and it was a beautiful sunny day in
we walked her halfway across town and
in the wheelchair and we found this
great French restaurant
we wheeled her in there and she
didn't get her
evening glass of wine for
two weeks in the rehab and we're like
guess what she's like yeah
we didn't drink any she she had some so
enjoy
uh giving uh
make it nice okay Make It Sweet why you
are planting seeds you are planting
seeds for the actual ability okay this
two-day retreat
is a Buddha emanation planting retreat
Buddha emanation power
seed planting Retreat you will look back
on these days and say that's when I got
started
when you're a big Buddha you know
running your own universe
you can say it was back at Diamond
Mountain
that two-day Retreat you know I was
having fun with Eminem and all kinds of
cool stuff
I was Pinot Noir
for my mom who
okay cool
all right
[Music]
oh
I have a picture for you for what you
can give to the E Docs
Peachtree Cafe
cinnamon rolls
okay he talks especially like Kratos
love cinnamon rolls from pastries
so by the way Daniel pretty much built
that place and we should give him a hand
[Music]
[Applause]
and he and Juan Hustle they run it and
Johnny Johnny oison they run a
monthly TV show
because we don't have permission to
serve food so we serve TV shows
uh
but uh
it's called Peachtree world news
we have about close to 20 organizations
now
and it's hard to keep up with what's
going on
even for me I don't know I don't even
know which country John Brady's in at
the at the moment
uh he was teaching in Turkey
turkey and turkey and
then he was in Vienna and then he was
in the Philippines I don't know so
anyway Daniel and Juan Hustle have a
monthly news show and they kind of tell
you what's going on you know
be sure to if you want to be on the
mailing list talk to them
and they run it out of the Peace
[Music]
okay you can go to Peachtree world news
or YouTube channel
yeah cool
all right uh why am i showing this Cafe
yeah we're emanating it for the practice
I mean peace drink okay uh
now
what's the definition of a animal in
Buddhism everything has a definition
no lynching Koopa
yeah basically
low intelligence
Len means uh
uh can't understand
doesn't have the cognitive skills to
understand subtleties of language
if you yell at a dog they will
[Music]
but they can't understand a dharmatism
and Koopa means they can't teach a
Dharma teacher they don't have speaking
they don't have advanced speaking
ability yes there are dolphins who are
more intelligent than most of the guys
in rimra
uh but in general
uh
animals suffer from inability to think
clearly and they it's not fun to be an
animal
it's it's constant fear constant danger
the reason they keep looking over their
shoulders
is that if you don't you get eaten
and it's a doggy dog world it's it's a
terrible life and a frightening life to
be an animal
so what would be the best gift to give
to them
some kind of cognitive ability you know
like they could figure out the best hole
to stay in
when coyotes are out or you know stuff
like that if they could think more
clearly
they would be happier and safer
so what's the example the picture
I like this picture uh this was my
three-year Retreat I think it's the
first
picture of me teaching the pimp
and I think it was 2001 or something
like that and
basically
I I really really like the picture
because I was also skinnier
uh and I had more hair but um
also I think uh to me
to be able to give the animals The Gift
of the pen
that they could understand the pen
like
if you could teach an animal
that their seeds are creating their
world wouldn't that be sweet
so if you when you emanate
for the animals right in the next two
days
emanate as a teacher who can teach a dog
to pin
emanate as someone who can communicate
the pen
to a to an animal
and emanate yourself
speaking to the animals
and and my experience in my three year
Retreat as I mentioned if you don't
speak for about six months you learn to
communicate on a basic level with
animals
and and it's a lot of fun we had
a pet rabbit who would come to the door
knock on the door
demand cookies refuse chocolate chip
cookies
I demand what's a scotch
shortbread
she remembers buying them my rabbit
would only eat those
she's like I give her a chocolate chip
cookies like
she's like
they speak with their body language and
she's like don't
you didn't y'all say go out for
Scottish butter cookies
okay so imagine that you can communicate
with the
animals and and make them understand the
pen and then they they find their life
would be not so good okay
all right
this namje means uh the ability
to grasp
to analyze things the ability to analyze
their life in terms of seeds
the ability to analyze their life
in terms of seeds
I saw a coyote today
sneaking around our home
yeah was he scary yeah well maybe you
should stop scaring all the little
insects you know you know I'm talking to
a rabbit right
and uh so you know this give them this
kind of
wisdom to take responsibility for their
world that it's coming from them every
irritating person you ever met
was coming from you
there's a famous incident in this Temple
right around there
where there was a new student who came
here and we had just finished the day
before a class about how you're creating
all the people around you and she was
standing there and we were all talking
and she said I'm surrounded by idiots
you know and we're all like
yeah
okay so if you could teach her a rabbit
to think like that that's the greatest
that's the tongue land sorry that's the
tone you're gonna do for for the animal
realm and you can pick your own animals
and and you don't forget you're working
up to
being a gay way
a Dharma teacher for them and by the end
of the meditation on the rabbits
they should get enlightened okay in each
realm that you visit
the end of the story is all the rabbits
are in life
okay like don't forget what we did in
the hot house he doesn't repeat it for
every will we gain a luxury apartment we
gave them some nice food and drink
he gave me some fancy clothes
then we taught them to meditate made me
taught them Dharma and then finally they
became a Dharma teacher
okay so when you visit a realm in this
meditation for the next two days
uh do that by the way
some Realms you can see
and some Realms you cannot see
okay and you're just gonna have to get
used to that you know can you see quarks
no you're taking it for granted by the
people who invented your cell phone
they do you have a cell phone yes does
it work yes was it made by somebody yes
do they believe in quarks yes do you
believe in quarks well since I have a
cell phone yes
okay you can't see all the Realms that
doesn't mean they're not there
okay talk to people who understand
talk to them Steve Jobs's they'll tell
you about quarks can you see quarks no
will you ever understand quarks no uh
but do you trust team Johns yeah he gave
me my cell phone you know so it's the
same with hell realms
okay it's the same with cold hell Realms
okay there's some things you'll never
see
I had the best yoga class in my whole
life in Hong Kong one time David Swenson
who is the only guy who ever filmed to
even moved sorry
Stanga level two and three the only
person in history to film them
and he got up he came to my three year
Retreat and taught me yoga
and he got up in Hong Kong and the first
thing he said was listen
there's some yoga poses you will never
be able to do
we're all like
here and he said everybody's body's
still different you know it's just it's
not gonna happen some things you just
can't do there's some things you're not
going to be able to see for a while
that doesn't mean those yoga poses don't
exist
it just means you can't do it yet
all right he can do them by the way and
it's fun to watch him because he's very
modest
he's very kind in that makes him a real
Yogi
all right
just to have a yoga teacher tell me
look there's certain exotic poses you
will never do there's certain normal
poses you'll never do guess in Minecraft
then I'm like thank you you know okay
he clumps together
the Deep transformation
meditations for the rest of the being
which means
[Music]
and me
uh demigods worldly gods and humans okay
he just clumps them together
and here's the picture and I don't need
to say anything else
they want stuff
okay
humans
worldly Gods worldly demigods they just
want more shopping malls
okay so just emanate as bigger and
bigger shopping malls with more and more
useless stuff
okay and they'll be happy
it's very easy for the higher realms
they just want more stuff
impossible I love this movie called what
is it The Bodyguard not that one
there's a lady who hires a guy to carry
her shopping bags
and then he carries them he walks behind
her and carries the shopping bags and
she goes home every day and and opens up
this huge closet and just throws the
bags in and never wears the clothes you
know
it's kind of where the higher Realms are
out they just want more stuff
okay now
I had a hesitation here is it ethical to
pile more stuff on a higher realm person
I mean it's just gonna make him a happy
right oh oh you don't like a Tesla Z you
want the Tesla XD you know yeah okay oh
you want the red one yeah okay trading
you're a black one you know you know and
then uh
is it okay to do that in this meditation
Daniel
decide before you do it before you try
it you have to decide whether you wanna
overload
higher realm beings with charge keys
well it's like eventually they figure
out that it's not actually going to make
them happy so you're getting them to
that realization faster I think yeah
pile them up with more luxury cars until
they finally get sick of them
all right it's ethical
since you have as a Buddha you have
Limitless power to CR to emanate new
cars for them
they are getting into you and slamming
the door
and driving off in you
get into the understand you're not
giving them a card you are your one you
are messing with the elements of
existence
you are effing with the atoms
you're turning yourself into it into the
next test line
and you're saying drive me
I'm happy
just drive me I saw a winning corner in
San Diego
Bentley oh my God I don't want one don't
buy me one I won't take it
someone offered me the best Tesla and I
I sold it before it was delivered and we
gave it to the mixed nuts
uh so anyway
be a be a beautiful car become a
beautiful car give them give them
everything
okay
uh we got four more minutes I'll use it
he says
demigods like to have better weapons
and body armor kocha means body armor
those of you who are studying baji
yogini you know gocha
foreign you know for for a worldly gods
give them better and better food and
stuff like that
meaning
but humans have more desire than all of
them is that humans are at the top of
the food chain desire they want even
more so what are you gonna become for
them
whatever the heck they want
okay it's Limitless
there's no limit on the things that
human beings want just become the next
popular thing
okay the next popular useless Gadget
become you become happily
oh you wanna
I don't know I saw weird stuff lately
like a dog proof scooper upper
that works on compressed air and
you know cleans itself oh you want one
of those okay I'm there you know
I'll suck it up okay again
to launcher
Denny says
get them Gator means Bank coming bank
account
it the literal meaning is root of virtue
if you ever translate it that way it's
again I will kill you
it doesn't mean root of virtue it means
your your credit card your karma give
them karmi credit cards
with lots of
loaded up
loaded up Carmen credit card
hand them out
kame
loaded karmic credit card
you're not offering credit card you
you are the credit card okay
okay like John Brady is going to be
Discover card
I'm Gonna Be American Express
okay like that okay so
being creative
have fun
it says Zoom for a hundred dollars he
says
who said it first
hagony Haggerty hundred dollars
yeah if you don't come in here on Friday
with a big Zoo
foreign
for two days
if you if
if you do this meditation for two days
and you're not have a big dumb smile on
your face by Friday then I know you
didn't you didn't do a real retreat
all right by the way Friday morning will
release the boundary
and you can
talk again
and not before that Whispering is still
talking
okay we established that in the second
three-year retreat
okay all right
I mean I'm not saying everybody but
but I did see it
happen uh
Denny's gonna get into and we'll stop
there for the first class we'll take a
half hour break but
just to make sure you don't go away
uh he's gonna go into
what would you like to emanate for the
enlightened beings
what do they want
what would they like to see you turn
into do they need a credit card or
so you won't find out
what you're gonna be unless you come
back for the next class
see you in half an hour
[Music]